<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Stop Rate Increases</string>

    <string name="summary">In recent years, Saratoga has seen tremendous increases in water rates, and this is a protest email which
        pushes back against these rate increases. Your email will be sent to CPUC(California Public Utilities Commission) Regulators
        and other interested parties, such as the City Council Office and the San Jose Water Company. By sending a protest letter,
        you acknowledge that the inflation in water prices is unjust, unreasonable, and unfairly discriminatory against Saratoga residents.
        You will receive a copy of your email as well.
    </string>

    <string name="details">Dear PUC President Picker and Commissioners,\n\n
        San Jose Water Company’s Advice Letter 523 will lead to a rate increase of 3.75% and $13.7M. SJWC is requesting surcharges to offset increase in purchased water, ground water extraction and recycled water charges. My protest is based upon (6) The relief requested in the advice letter is unjust, unreasonable, or discriminatory. Yes, the request is unreasonable and unjust. Since 2010 they have made profits that total $281.2M Their INCOME INCREASED FROM $17M in 2010 to $59.2M in 2017  i.e a whopping 248% increase in profits since 2010. How many Silicon Valley Companies have achieved this in a consumer focused industry?  Well, making a profit is NOT a bad thing in Silicon Valley, it is expected. But not on the backs of a consumer that does NOT have a choice or is willingly making a choice? We are cutting our water consumption - we don’t want to buy the product - but our water rates continue to go up! Do you see what we are trying to say here? Can a regulated company do so well?\n\n
        I urge you to also deny SJWC\'s GRC application.  Enough is enough. I am NOT ready to accept or support any more rate increases until a thorough investigation and audit of San Jose Water Company is completed. SJWC has proposed A.18.01-004  due to escalating operating expenses related to water quality and safety requirements, as well as significant system infrastructure replacement requirements as the water system ages over the next several years.  I believe SJWC has done very well the past few years – How have their profits been applied? How much is needed for these projects?\n\n
        We urge you to NOT approve any mergers or acquisitions with San Jose Water but review every proposal methodically to gauge the impacts to the customers of San Jose Water Company.\n\n
        We urge you to NOT approve any rate increase until the investigation and audit of San Jose Water is completed.\n\n
        Please review petition to replace SJWC with a municipal utility company http://www.tinyurl.com/noMoreSJWC - YES, I have signed it along with 2600+ others. Just compare the difference in a San Jose Water Bill versus a City of Santa Clara Water Bill (Case Study I below). The data is quite clear. San Jose Water Company customers are paying a lot more for water. So here is stating the obvious. The San Jose Water Company is a monopoly! Thanks to no city council jurisdiction, SJWC has gotten behind a simple process of ‘gaming the system’ submitting Advice Letters and Rate Case filings to CPUC and getting the approvals.\n\n
        THANK YOU TO CPUC COMMISSIONERS, STAFF AND ORA\n
        We appreciate your diligence in taking a measured and tough stand against a greedy and shameless corporation called San Jose Water Company. We are a choice less consumer but not voiceless consumer.\n
        Please stand by us, the people. You are all doing an amazing job, standing up for us citizens! Your staff and ORA are collectively doing an impressive job so far and we commend you for it!\n
        Thank you for rejecting AL 501 and AL 510 and initiating the audit and investigation of San Jose Water Company.\n
        We thank you for noting that San Jose Water Company has had a windfall $59.2M profit in 2017 (up from $21M in 2012) – while we citizens have no choice, but to keep paying more and more to SJWC thanks to the super high water bills. We thank you ENOUGH IS ENOUGH!\n
        We appreciate you pushing back on the rampant rate increases of San Jose Water Company that we have been dealing with.\n\n
        FURTHER CALL TO ACTION AND SUMMARY OF OUR REQUEST\n
        We urge CPUC to continue to be consumer advocate and consider implementing the following:\n
        1. We need more of our money back. Thanks for rejecting SJWC proposal AL No. 510 CREDIT SURCHARGE. SJWC owes its customers a lot more than $1,794,439.\n
        2. DO NOT APPROVE ANY MERGER REQUESTS WITHOUT CONSIDERING THE IMPACT UPON THE CITIZENS\n
        3. CONDUCT A THOROUGH INVESTIGATION AND AUDIT: We are glad that CPUC initiated a thorough investigation and audit of SJWC\'s past and present billing practices Please penalize SJWC for any wrong doings and public reprimand any wrong practices currently in place.\n
        4. NO FURTHER RATE INCREASE IN 2018: SJWC\'s greed won\'t end.  Please don\'t approve any more rate increases in 2018. CPUC has approved Letters 498, 506, 508, 509, 513A in 2017 == 16.52%. This is more than what we anticipated for 2017, given the consumer gouging that occurred in 2016.\n
        5. THOROUGH SCRUTINY OF COST OF CAPITAL AND GENERAL RATE INCREASES BEFORE ANY RATE INCREASES ARE GRANTED:  Please consider comparison metrics for all other public AND private utilities in the bay area in determining the appropriate cost of capital adjustments and rate increases for future years.  Please make sure that we have comparable rates and/or implement policies so our rates get normalized over the coming years. There is plenty of evidence in APPENDIX A through I below that our rates have gone up astronomically in the last few years.\n
        6. THOROUGH SCRUTINY OF EVERYTHING SJWC SUBMITS AND HAS SUBMITTED IN THE PAST:  As part of the audit, please evaluate all the filings by SJWC currently in place. Table 1 and 2 below shows a summary view of the exploitation that has been conducted surgically and methodically by San Jose Water Company these last few years. SJWC has stacked the system to suit it’s greed and it is time, we pull the plug on that. As you read through this email, please make a mental note that some San Jose Water customers have seen their 2016 water bill to be in the $2,500 to $4,000 range, in spite of reducing their water consumption by ~50%. Simply stated, San Jose Water Company has been blatantly exploiting their customers in the name of drought for increased profits.\n
        7. WE NEED COMPARISON METRICS – we have had enough of SJWC’s effort to blatantly increase profits If CPUC approves anything from SJWC, please provide us as part of the disposition, a study of Bay Area public and private water utility companies:
        \t a)What has been the % increase in water rates year to year since 2007 – obviously includes specific data SJWC.\n
        \t b)In particular, what is the percentage increase these utility companies are planning in 2017, given that SJWC is currently filed to increase rates  at least 20%.\n\n

        I AM VERY UPSET – I FEEL I HAVE BEEN EXPLOITED BY SJWC\n
        THEY CONTINUE TO LEVERAGE THE PROCESS FOR INCREASED PROFITS\n
        SJWC has increased revenue in the period of 2010 to 2016 by 66% and in the same time their income has gone up by 200% - as per Table 1 below They continue to increase rates every year. The customer base is a constant – why are we seeing such huge increases? We are being exploited and I am afraid this is only the beginning now that SJWC has experienced the bounty.\n\n

        AL 510: WE WANT MORE THAN “PUBLIC RELATION PITTANCE” aka Letter 510\n
        The total amount of the refund is $1,794,439–Just $1.794,439? That is ridiculous!!!\n
        We call it PR Pittance\n
        \t 1. I am appalled that SJWC still seeks to increase our rates, and the surcharge given the financial windfall for SJWC in 2016 on the backs of a severe drought, and the people of our community who went through a lot of personal stress due to super high water bills.\n
        \t 2. Here is a petition asking Santa Clara County to take action, condemn San Jose Water Company http://tinyurl.com/CondemnedSJWC\n
        \t 3. We demand more of our cash back. Per the annual statement of SJWC, SJWC increased their profits 40% from 2015 to 2016. Their Q3 2016 income was $19M in comparison to Q3 2015 of $9.5M.\n
        \t 4. We the customers of SJWC, ask that SJWC refund the delta increase, the “drought bumper bonanza” that they have raked in, in a dire drought. The customers of SJWC are definitely entitled to a refund much more than $1.7M not this “PR Pittance”. I do understand the need for a serious PR makeover, but this is not even a start! The graph in the appendix under section CASE STUDY F: SJWC 350% increase since 2010 demonstrates how a homeowner reduced consumption by 30-50% over the past 7 years HOWEVER SJWC rate has increased 350% in the same time period. This is not justified, nor fair and I ask CPUC to step up and stop this blatant gouging of the consumer.\n\n

        Overall, In my opinion SJWC does not deserve any increase in rates given how much profit they are currently making. Please protect the people.\n
        I urge you to deny SJWC\'s GRC application.  Enough is enough. I am NOT ready to accept or support any more rate increases until a thorough investigation and audit of San Jose Water Company is completed.\n
        No more automatic approvals. No more rate increases. In fact, we want our money back. Thank you.\n
</string>

    <string name="emails_TO">water_division@cpuc.ca.gov, public.advisor@cpuc.ca.gov, ora@cpuc.ca.gov, jb5@cpuc.ca.gov</string>

    <string name="emails_CC">senator.beall@senate.ca.gov, John.Baker@cpuc.ca.gov, matthew.marcus@cpuc.ca.gov, raminder.kahlon@cpuc.ca.gov,
        tkm@cpuc.ca.gov, michael.picker@cpuc.ca.gov, elizabeth.podolinsky@cpuc.ca.gov, carla.peterman@cpuc.ca.gov,
        liane.randolph@cpuc.ca.gov, rachel.peterson@cpuc.ca.gov, rkumar@saratoga.ca.us, lester.wong@cpuc.ca.gov,
        martha.guzman-aceves@cpuc.ca.gov, michael.minkus@cpuc.ca.gov, clifford.rechtschaffen@cpuc.ca.gov, sean.Simon@cpuc.ca.gov,
        allison.brown@cpuc.ca.gov, lolita.hajian@cpuc.ca.gov
    </string>

    <string name="kumar_email">rkumar@saratoga.ca.us</string>
    <string name="ujjwal_email">ujjwal.krishnamurthi@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="email_subject">AL 523 and GRC 18–01–004</string>
    <string name="petition_text">Thanks for your submission!\nYour complaint has been recorded. Please sign this petition to show your support.
    </string>
</resources>
